Guide to the Roger Bagnall papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Roger Bagnall Papers,
1967-2001
Bagnall, Roger S.
21 linear feet (46 document boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library New York, NY. 10027
5012593
Biographical Note
Roger Bagnall is a papyrologist and a historian of the Hellenistic, Roman, and late antique eastern Mediterranean specializing in Graeco-Roman Egypt.
Scope and Content
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 17 series:
Series I: Education
Series II: Books, 1971-2000
Series III: Chronology 1
Series IV: Series IV. Chronology 2
Series V: Egypt in Late Antiquity and Kellis Account Book
Series VI: Demography
Series VII: Articles
Series VIII: Lectures and Unpublished Work
Series IX: Ancient History Courses at Columbia
Series X: Sabbaticles, Travels Congresses
Series XI: Professional Activities
Series XII: NEH Summer Seminars & Written and Unwritten Conference
Series XIII: Macedonia Symposium 1989
Series XIV: Columbia University Activities, 1974-2001
Series XV: Information Technology
Series XVI: Commission on the Future of Libraries
Series XVII: Professional Correspondence
Subjects
Bagnall, Roger S.; Egypt--Civilization--332 B.C.-638 A.D.; Egypt--Civilization--638-1798.; Egypt--History.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
Gift of Roger Bagnall December 12, 2000
- Series I. Education
  - Athens, American School, 1967, 1970/71 (Box 1)
  - Canada Council (Box 1)
  - College Admissions (Box 1)
  - Draft (Box 1)
  - Duke (Box 1)
  - High School and Earlier Memorabilia (Box 1)
  - Massey College (Box 1)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 1)
  - Summer Seminar in Papyrology 1968 (Box 1)
  - Toronto (Box 1)
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation (Box 1)
  - Yale (Box 1)
  - Yale Faculty, General (Box 1)
  - Yale Classics Department (Box 1)
  - York University (Box 1)
- Series II. Books, 1971-2000
  - Administration of the Ptolemaic Possessions outside Egypt, ( Correspondence) (Box 2, Folder A 2)
  - Administration of the Ptolemaic Possessions outside Egypt Chapter 9 Notes (Box 2, Folder A 2)
  - Ostraka in the Royal Ontario Museum II (Box 2, Folder A 4)
  - The Florida Ostraka (Box 2, Folder A 5)
  - Checklist of Editions of Greek Papyri and Ostraca (Box 2, Folder A 7)
  - Columbia Papyri VII: 4th Century Documents from Karanis (Box 2, Folder A 9)
  - Greek Ostraka (Box 2, Folder A 10)
  - Greek Historical Documents: The Hellenistic Period (Box 2, Folder A 11)
  - Currency and Inflation in 4th Century Egypt (Box 2, Folder A 13)
  - Consuls of the Later Roman Empire, ( Correspondence) (Box 2, Folder A 14)
  - Consuls of the Later Roman Empire Inter-author working papers (Box 2, Folder A 14)
  - Columbia Papyri VIII (Box 2, Folder A 15)
  - Checklist of Editions of Greek and Latin Papyri, Ostraca and Tablets 4th Ed. (Box 2, Folder A 16)
  - Reading Papyri, Writing Ancient History (Box 2, Folder A 19)
  - Columbia Papyri X (Box 2, Folder A 20)
  - The Census Register P. Oxy. 984 (Box 2, Folder A 21)
- III. Chronology 1
  - The Chronological Systems of Byzantine Egypt, ( Publication) (Box 3, Folder A 6)
  - The Chronological Systems of Byzantine Egypt, [n.p.], 1977-8, ( Correspondence) (Box 3, Folder A 6)
  - Regnal Formulas in Byzantine Egypt, [n.p.], 1979, ( Correspondence) (Box 3, Folder A 8)
  - Bagnall-Worp Chronology, [n.p.], 1980, ( Correspondence) (Box 3)
  - Chronological Notes on Byzantine Documents (Box 3)
  - Consuls of the Later Roman Empire (Box 3)
  - Chronology Correspondence (non-Worp) (Box 3)
  - Bagnall-Worp Chronology, [n.p.], 1981, ( Correspondence) (Box 3)
- Series IV. Chronology 2
  - Bagnall-Worp Chronology, [n.p.], 1982, ( Correspondence) (Box 4)
  - Bagnall-Worp Chronology, [n.p.], 1983-4, ( Correspondence) (Box 4)
  - Bagnall-Worp Chronology, [n.p.], 1985, ( Correspondence) (Box 4)
  - Bagnall-Worp Chronology, [n.p.], 1986, ( Correspondence) (Box 4)
  - Bagnall-Worp Chronology, [n.p.], 1987-8, ( Correspondence) (Box 4)
  - Bagnall-Worp Chronology, [n.p.], 1989-90, ( Correspondence) (Box 4)
  - Bagnall-Worp Chronology, [n.p.], 1991-6, ( Correspondence) (Box 4)
- Series V: Egypt in Late Antiquity and Kellis Account Book
  - Egypt in Late Antiquity, Princeton Press, ( Permissions, artwork, correspondence) (Box 5, Folder A 17)
  - Egypt in Late Antiquity, ( Outline, notes, database info) (Box 5, Folder A 17)
  - Egypt in Late Antiquity Brown, JohnReligion chapter (Box 5, Folder A 17)
  - Kellis Agricultural Account Book Jenkins/Wagner version (Box 5, Folder A 22)
  - Kellis Agricultural Account Book, ( Correspondence) (Box 5, Folder A 22)
  - Kellis Agricultural Account Book, ( Correspondence and notes) (Box 5, Folder A 22)
- Series VI: Demography
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, ( Frier Correspondence 1) (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, ( Frier Correspondence 2) (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, ( Correspondence) (Box 6)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, Berkeley (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, Berlin (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, Cairo (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, Florence (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, Giessen (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, London (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, Michigan (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, Milan (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, Oxford (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, Paris (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, Princeton, Strasbourg (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - Demography of Roman Egypt, Vienna (Box 6, Folder A 18)
  - "Beginnings of the Roman Census in Egypt" (Box 6, Folder D 105)
  - "Census Declarations from Tebtunis" (Box 6, Folder D 115)
  - "Census Declarations in the Berlin Collection" (Box 6, Folder D 116)
  - "Census Declarations from the British Library" (Box 6, Folder D 126)
  - "The Affairs of a Complex Family" (Box 6, Folder D 122)
- Series VII: Articles
  - Papyri Greek and Egyptian ed (Box 7, Folder B 4)
  - "Nomination of a Goldsmith to Collect Taxes" (Box 7, Folder B 6)
  - "Wax Tablets in the Pierpont Morgan Library" (Box 7, Folder B 7)
  - "The Fayum and its People" (Box 7, Folder B 11)
  - "Status and Law" (Box 7, Folder B 12)
  - "I papiri e la storia" (Box 7, Folder B 13)
  - "Fayum," "Papyrus," "Parchment," "Rent" (Box 7, Folder B 14)
  - "Two 4th-Century Accounts from Kellis" (Box 7, Folder B 18)
  - "A Property Division from Aphrodito" (Box 7, Folder B 19)
  - "Stolos the Admiral" (Box 7, Folder D 8)
  - "Three Notes on Ptolemaic Inscriptions" (Box 7, Folder D 9)
  - "Orders for Payment from a Banker's Archive: Papyri in the Collection of FSU" (Box 7, Folder D 15)
  - "Papyrology" (Box 7, Folder D 21)
  - "Army and Police in Roman Upper Egypt" (Box 7, Folder D 24)
  - "Notes on Egyptian and Greek Ostraka" (Box 7, Folder D 31)
  - "The Consuls of A.D. 411-412" (Box 7, Folder D 32)
  - "Ostraka from the Yale Collection" (Box 7, Folder D 36)
  - "The Date of the Foundation of Alexandria" (Box 7, Folder D 45)
  - "Egypt, the Ptolemies, and the Greek World" (Box 7, Folder D 56)
  - "Christian Invocations in the Papyri" (and supplement) (Box 7, Folder D 58-59)
  - "Due papiri fiorentini del quarto secolo" (Box 7, Folder D 61)
  - "The Population of Theadelphia in the Fourth Century" (Box 7, Folder D 64)
  - "Religious Conversion and Onomastic Change" (Box 7, Folder D 65)
  - "Two Fourth-Century Papyri in Bologna" (Box 7, Folder D 69)
  - "The Fourth-Century Tax Roll in the Princeton Collection: A Reedition" (Box 7, Folder D 71)
  - "Three Papyri from Fourth-Century Karanis" (Box 7, Folder D 75)
  - "Publius Petronius, Augustan Prefect of Egypt" (Box 7, Folder D 77)
  - "Agricultural Productivity and Taxation in Fourth-Century Egypt" (Box 7, Folder D 79)
  - "Two Byzantine Legal Papyri in a Private Collection" (Box 7, Folder D 81)
  - "Dating by the Moon in Nubian Inscriptions" (Box 7, Folder D 83)
  - "Papyri and Ostraka from Quseir al-Quadim" (Box 7, Folder D 84)
  - "Papyri and Ostraka from Quseir al-Quadim", ( photos) (Box 7, Folder D 84)
  - "Greeks and Egyptians: Ethnicity, Status, and Culture" (Box 7, Folder D 89)
  - "Restoring the Text of Documents" (Box 7, Folder D 90)
  - "Archaeology and Papyrology" (Box 7, Folder D 94)
  - "The Hellenistic Environment", ( Walters Catalogue Essay) (Box 7, Folder D 95)
  - "Official and Private Violence in Roman Egypt" (Box 7, Folder D 97)
  - "Five Problematic Fourth-Century Pieces" (Box 7, Folder D 99)
  - "Notes on Roman and Byzantine Documents" (Box 8)
  - "An Owner of Literary Papyri" (Box 8, Folder D 107)
  - "Military Officers as Landowners in 4th Century Egypt" (Box 8, Folder D 108)
  - "Ptolemaic Administration of Palestine" (Box 8, Folder D 109)
  - "Combat ou vide: Christianisme et paganisme dans l'Egypte romaine tardive" (Box 8, Folder D 110)
  - "Landholding in Late Roman Egypt: the Distribution of Wealth" (Box 8, Folder D 112)
  - "Count Ausonius" (Box 8, Folder D 113)
  - "Greek and Latin Documents from 'Abu Sha'ar, 1990-1", ( Correspondence) (Box 8, Folder D 123 & D 125)
  - "Greek and Latin Documents from 'Abu Sha'ar, 1990-1", ( Photographs) (Box 8, Folder D 123 & D 125)
  - "Egypt and the 'Barbarians'" (Box 8, Folder D 128)
  - "Governmental Roles in the Economy of Late Antiquity" (Box 8, Folder D 129)
  - "SPP XX 74: The Last Preserved Bank-Diagraphe" (Box 8, Folder D 130)
  - "Franks in Sixth-century Egypt" (Box 8, Folder D 134)
  - "The Painted Garden of Coptos" (Box 8, Folder D 135)
  - "A Ptolemaic Inscription from Bir 'Iayyan" (Box 8, Folder D 136)
  - "Missing Females in Roman Egypt" (Box 8, Folder D 138)
  - "Decolonizing Ptolemaic Egypt" (Box 8, Folder D 139)
  - "Lender, Borrower, and Banker in P. Yale I 65" (Box 8, Folder D 153)
  - "Eirene to Epaphrys: P. Yale I 77 revised" (Box 8, Folder D 154)
  - "Your Wife in Your Name: P. Oxy. LXII 4340" (Box 8, Folder D 155)
  - "'He darkened our reasoning': A note on CPR XIV 52" (Box 8, Folder D 157)
  - "Jesus Reads a Book" (Box 8, Folder D 158)
  - "A Prefect's Edict Mentioning Sacrifice" (Box 8, Folder D 159)
  - "TETPAXPYΕON" (Box 8, Folder D 162)
- Series VIII: Lectures and Unpublished Work
  - Alexandria Library (Dial) (Box 9)
  - Ancient Public Administration (University Seminar) (Box 9)
  - Athanasius (Box 9)
  - Athens in the Dark Age, ( Senior thesis and rejected article) (Box 9)
  - Berenike lecture (Box 9)
  - Christianization of the Roman Empire (AAH 1995) (Box 9)
  - Dorymenes of Aetolia (Box 9)
  - Eastern Desert Project, [n.p.], 1975/1976 (Box 9)
  - Ends of Famous Greeks and Romans (Box 9)
  - Hellenistic Cities Panel, comment (Box 9)
  - Kraus papyri (Box 9)
  - Lewis, Greeks in Ptolemaic Egypt, reprint (Box 9)
  - Literature and Literacy (University of Minnesota conference on the book) (Box 9)
  - London ostraka (Box 9)
  - Papyri as Evidence for Trade (AIA 1997) (Box 9)
  - People of Roman Egypt, Metropolitan Museum, Brown (Box 9)
  - Ptolemaic empire and its effects (Box 9)
  - Reader's adviser (Box 9)
  - Travel Dynamics Cruises, [n.p.], 1979, 1990 (Box 9)
  - Yale Classical Studies (abandoned reprint) (Box 9)
- Series IX: Ancient History Courses at Columbia
  - Classical Civilization 3159: Wealth and Poverty, [n.p.], 1974 (Box 10)
  - Classical Civilization 3162: Ancient Law, [n.p.], 1978, 1979, 1984, 1985, 1986, 1988 (Box 10)
  - History 3806: Trade and Exploration, [n.p.], 1975 (Box 10)
  - History W4013: Studies in the Social and Economic History of the Greek World, [n.p.], 1975 (Box 10)
  - History 4030: Classical Greece, [n.p.], 1980, 1982, 1985, 1986 (Box 10)
    [Includes 3977 seminar 1983]
  - History 4040: Alexander the Great (Box 10)
  - History 8056: Greek City (Box 10)
- Series X: Sabbaticles, Travels Congresses
  - Sabbatical: 1984-5 New York, New York, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Sabbatical:1990-1 New York, New York, 1990-1 (Box 11)
  - Sabbatical:1995-6 Oxford, Oxford, 1995-6 (Box 11)
  - Sabbatical: 2000-1 (travel), [n.p.], 2000-1 (Box 11)
  - Travel: 1981 Italy, Italy, 1981 (Box 11)
  - Travel: 1988, 1989 Italy, Italy, 1988-9 (Box 11)
  - Travel: 1991 England, Netherlands, Germany, Austria, England, Netherlands, Germany, Austria, 1991 (Box 11)
  - Travel: 1993 France, England, France, England, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Travel: 1994 Finland, Finland, 1994 (Box 11)
  - Travel: 1996 Jordan, Syria, Israel, Egypt, Germany, Jordan, Syria, Israel, Egypt, Germany, 1996 (Box 11)
  - Travel: 2000 Iowa, Iowa, 2000 (Box 11)
  - Conferences: Congresses of Papyrology, [n.p.], 1983-1998 (Box 11)
  - Conferences: IWPSH (Box 11)
  - Conferences: 1988 Toronto Law, Toronto, 1998 (Box 11)
  - Conferences: 1990 Symposion, [n.p.], 1990 (Box 11)
  - Conferences: 1990 Demotic Congress, [n.p.], 1990 (Box 11)
  - Conferences: The Greek and Roman Book, Minnesota, 1993 (Box 11)
- Series XI: Professional Activities
  - American Council of Learned Societies (Box 12)
  - American Historical Association: Breasted Prize Committee, [n.p.], 1989 (Box 12)
  - American Society of Papyrologists (Box 12)
  - Association of Ancient Historians (Box 12)
  - Brazil Project (Box 12)
  - BASP 26-31 Typesetting (Box 12)
  - CAARI - other (Box 12)
  - CAARI - Giraud Foster, ( Correspondence) (Box 12)
  - Classical Micropublishing Inc. (Box 13)
  - Copyright Law (Box 13)
  - Council on Library Resources (Box 13)
  - Egyptological Seminar (Box 13)
  - FIEC, Dublin, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Florida State University (Box 13)
  - Fondation Francqui (Box 13)
  - Inamori Fdn. (Box 13)
  - Library of Congress Conference, [n.p.], 1987 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Professional (Box 13)
  - NEH Challenge Grant Panel (Box 13)
  - NEH Summer Stipend, [n.p.], 1994 (Box 13)
  - New York State Panel (Box 13)
  - Scholars Press (Box 13)
  - Terra Publishing (Box 13)
  - Trans Fiction (Box 13)
  - UC Santa Barbara (Box 13)
- Series XII: NEH Summer Seminars & Written and Unwritten Conference
  - NEH Summer Seminar, [n.p.], 1987, ( Application, correspondence) (Box 14)
  - NEH Summer Seminar, [n.p.], 1987, ( Report and follow-up) (Box 14)
  - NEH Summer Seminar, [n.p.], 1990, ( Application, correspondence, administration) (Box 14)
  - NEH Summer Seminar, [n.p.], 1990, ( Applicants and publicity) (Box 14)
  - NEH Summer Seminar, [n.p.], 1990, ( Correspondence) (Box 14)
  - NEH Summer Seminar, [n.p.], 1990, ( Travel arrangements) (Box 14)
  - NEH Summer Seminar, [n.p.], 1990, ( Report and follow-up) (Box 14)
  - Written and Unwritten, [n.p.], 1992, ( General) (Box 14)
  - Written and Unwritten, [n.p.], 1992, ( Participant correspondence) (Box 14)
  - NEH Summer Seminar, [n.p.], 1999, ( Society and Culture in Roman Egypt) (Box 14)
- Series XIII: Macedonia Symposium 1989
  - Macedonia, ( Administration) (Box 15)
  - Macedonia, ( Pan-Macedonian Association) (Box 15)
  - Macedonia, ( Macedonian-Canadian Human Rights Committee) (Box 15)
  - Macedonia, ( Contributions) (Box 15)
  - Macedonia, ( Financial Records) (Box 15)
  - Macedonia, ( Participant Correspondence) (Box 15)
- Series XIV: Columbia University Activities 1974-2001
  - Ad Hoc Committees (Box 16)
  - Art History Plan (not adopted), [n.p.], 1993 (Box 16)
  - Biermann, F.J. (Box 16)
  - Columbia Appointment Letters and Correspondence (Box 16)
  - Columbia University Correspondence, misc. (Box 16)
  - Columbia Junior Faculty Research Support, [n.p.], 1974-1978 (Box 16)
  - English Department Acting Chair, [n.p.], 2000-2001 (Box 16)
  - GSAS Deanship (Box 16)
  - GSAS Deanship Press Coverage (Box 16)
  - History Department New Fellowship Plan, [n.p.], 1989 (Box 16)
  - Law School: Teaching (Box 16)
  - Law School: Schiller Library and Memorial Volume (Box 16)
  - Margaret Thompson Honorary Degree, [n.p.], 1986 (Box 16)
  - Roman Law Search, [n.p.], 1985-1986 (Box 16)
  - Rome Agreement (Center for International Scholarly Exchange) and RSB paper on learned societies (Box 16)
  - Analysis, Documents, and Data (Box 17)
  - Minutes and Correspondence (Box 17)
  - Background (Box 17)
  - Housing Study (Box 17)
  - Housing Policy Statement (Box 17)
  - Capital Financing (Box 17)
  - Predecessor Committees (Box 17)
  - Litigation (Box 17)
  - Correspondence (Box 18)
  - Fraenkel Era Plans (Box 18)
  - Planning Data (Box 18)
  - Plans from Other Institutions (Box 18)
  - Teaching Loads Study (Box 18)
  - Humanities (Box 18)
  - Music (Box 18)
  - Natural Sciences (Box 18)
  - Social Sciences (Box 18)
  - Columbia University Libraries (Box 19)
  - School of Library Science Articles and Talks (Box 19)
  - School of Library Science Belanger and Rare Books (Box 19)
  - School of Library Science Deanship (Box 19)
  - School of Library Science Executive Committee (Box 19)
  - School of Library Science Faculty (Box 19)
  - Intner, Sheila S. (Box 19)
  - Project Aurora (Box 19)
  - Task Force on Information Processing (Box 19)
  - School of Library Science Background Info (Box 19)
  - School of Library Science Review Committee (Box 19)
- Series XV: Information Technology
  - ALA Preservation Microfilming Institute, [n.p.], 1986 (Box 20)
  - Bibliographie Papyrologique 1 (Box 20)
  - Bibliographie Papyrologique 2 (Box 20)
  - Center for Preservation of Micro Software (Box 20)
  - Classical Micropublishing Inc. (Box 20)
  - Classics Book-Scanning Project, [n.p.], 1987-89 (Box 20)
  - Correspondence on Technology (Box 20)
  - Ibycus (Box 20)
  - Information Technology Talk (British Academy) (Box 20)
  - Information Technology Talk (NY Classical Club) (Box 20)
  - Lille Conference, [n.p.], 1989 (Box 20)
  - NERCOMP Meeting, [n.p.], 1984 (Box 20)
  - Project Aurora (IBM) - Classics & Pew CD (Box 20)
  - Research Libraries Group (Box 20)
  - Technology Papers & Press - RSB (Box 20)
- Series XVI: Commission on the Future of Libraries
  - Opinion Papers: Battin, Stoan, Koenig (Box 21)
  - Capital Campaign (Box 21)
  - CUL Information (Box 21)
  - Correspondence (Box 21)
  - CLR Documents (Box 21)
  - Faculty Library Use Profiles (Box 21)
  - Commission Minutes (Box 21)
  - Preservation Committee, Correspondence and Report (Box 21)
  - Preservation Committee, Background (Box 21)
  - Commission Report (Box 21)
  - User Opinion and Letters (Box 21)
  - OCLC (Box 21)
  - Research Libraries Group (Box 21)
- Series XVII: Professional Correspondence
  - Allam, Nimet (Box 22)
  - Aly, Zaki (Box 22)
  - Bell, H.I. & Welles, C.B. (Box 22)
  - Brashear, William (Box 22)
  - Cvetler, Jiri (Box 22)
  - Drew-Bear, Th., ( 1971-1978) (Box 22)
  - Drew-Bear, Th., ( 1979-1988) (Box 22)
  - Eliassen, Martha (Box 22)
  - Gara, Alessandra (Box 22)
  - Gilliam, J.F. (Box 22)
  - Kupiszewski, Henryk (Box 22)
  - Luft, Ulrich (Box 23)
  - Marcovich, Miroslav (Box 23)
  - Naour, Christian (Box 23)
  - Polacek, Adalbert (Box 23)
  - Raschke, Manfred (Box 23)
  - Robert, Louis (Box 23)
  - Scherer, Jean (Box 23)
  - Schiller, A. Arthur and Erna (Box 23)
  - Shelton, John (Box 23)
  - Sijpesteijn, Pieter Johannes (Box 23)
  - Smith, Morton (Box 23)
  - Treadgold, Warren (Box 23)
  - Trell, Bluma (Box 23)
  - Turner, Eric G. (Box 23)
  - Wagner, Guy (Box 23)
  - Wall, Elbert (Box 23)
  - Weems, Sarah (Box 23)
  - Wehrli, Claude (Box 23)
  - Weinstein, Martha (Box 23)
  - Welles, C.B. (Box 23)
  - Willis, William H. (Box 23)
  - Wolff, Hans Julius (Box 23)
  - Youtie, H.C. and L. C. (Box 23)